Thiruchittrambalam S

E-MAIL : thiruchittrambalams@gmail.com

Contact No : 8122850436

PROFILE

Creative and proactive IT Analyst with over 3 years of experience in IT systems and software applications in computer systems. Seek to work in an environment with an opportunity where wealth and diversity of knowledge will be fully utilized which allows me to contribute to the continued growth and success of the organization and to my professional career.

Tried hands-on Forex and Crypto trading, as it did not work out as expected, looking for Job opportunities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Analyst, Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai Oct 2014 - Nov 2017

Business Development Associate, Byjus, Chennai Mar 2023 – June 2023

Pursuing DATA SCIENCE course in GUVI institute, chennai Present

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Informatica 9.6.1, Teradata,

Currently pursuing DATA SCIENCE course that includes python, pandas, sql, powerBI, machine learning

PROJECTS HANDLED

CLIENT: BRITISH AIRWAYS

DURATION: 2015-2017

ROLE: ETL Developer

ENVIRONMENT: Informatica 9.6, Unix, Teradata.

DESCRIPTION

British Airways deals with flight data. It consists of IATA code, source station, destination station, arrival time, departure time, connecting station for each flight and cabin details, number of passengers travelled etc. All this incoming data comes from flat file source. We extract the file by use of ETL and forecasting the BA flight passenger's count.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Involved in design, development, and maintenance of database for Data warehouse project.
- Involved in Business Users Meetings to understand their requirements.
- Designed, Developed and Supported Extraction, Transformation and Load Process (ETL) for data migration with Informatica 9.6
- Developed various mappings using Mapping Designer and worked with Aggregator, Lookup, Filter, Router, Joiner, Source Qualifier, Expression, Stored Procedure, Sorter and Sequence Generator transformations.

- Created complex mappings which involved Slowly Changing Dimensions, implementation of Business Logic and capturing the deleted records in the source systems.
- Created and scheduled Sessions, Jobs based on demand, run on time and run only once
- Monitored Workflows and Sessions using Workflow Monitor.
- Performed Unit testing, Integration testing and System testing of Informatica mappings.
- Coded SQL and Unix Scripts to capture data from different relational systems to flat file
- Created, launched & scheduled sessions.
- Used Server Manager to schedule sessions and batches.

ADDITIONAL DETAILS

- Handled single member project and rewarded by client.
- Organized team events during Client visits which helped me to improve my interaction skills with the team.
- Active participant in account level activities.
- Act as a trainer and trained 10 peoples at account level.
- Created technical level quiz in Organization portal
- School and college topper

BDA in BYJUS

- Effectively handled the clients
- Need creation and conversion of leads to revenue
- Achieved revenue target of Rs.50000 on weekly basis

EDUCATION SUMMARY

Degree	Institution	Aggregate (%)
B.E(Electronics and Instrumentation)	Velammal Engineering college, Anna University, Chennai	81.4
12 th	Gandhi Nagar Matric. Hr. sec School, Tiruvannamalai-606 601	96 (District 2nd Rank)
10 th	Gandhi Nagar Matric. Hr. sec School, Tiruvannamalai-606 601	93.2

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Name : S.Thiruchittrambalam

Father Name : P.Sambandam **DOB** : 06-11-1992

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all information mentioned above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Chennai Thiruchittrambalam S